# LAVENDA ACHIENG

## **ENGLISH TEACHER**



Nationality: Kenyan

D.O.B: 20th Jan 1994

#### - PROFILE -

CELTA qualified teacher with 2+ years' experience teaching children, adults and exam preparation. I enjoy utilizing my own activities in the classroom to help enhance the concepts we've learned in textbooks. I've been speaking English since I was a child.

#### CONTACT —

- Jiménez de la Espada 9, Cartagena 30204 Murcia, Spain
- +34 623 22 67 94
- teacherlavenda@outlook.com
- https://teacherlavenda.github.io
- in https://www.linkedin.com/in/teacherlavenda

# TEACHING EXPERIENCE -

## SEPT 2020 - PRESENT

Private English Teacher Freelance Cartagena, Spain

- Teaching ages from 5 to adults
- Face to face classes and online classes
- Conversation and Trinity ISE exam preparation
- Use a variety of materials and resources
- Successfully taught each student to pass intermediate levels within 5 months
- Younger students were able to communicate basic needs in English after 3 months

# OTHER EXPERIENCE

## **SEPT 2016 - FEB 2017**

Social Worker Migori District Hospital *Migori, Kenya* 

- Provision of counselling, advice and support to individuals
- Help children, elderly and families to solve their problems
- First aid provision
- · Risk management
- Recognising the signs of child abuse

## **EDUCATION**

# **DEC 2022**

Oxford TEFL Barcelona, Spain

#### Workshops

- Teaching Business English
- Teaching Cambridge Exam Classes
- Teaching Young Learners

#### **SEPT 2022**

Oxford TEFL Barcelona, Spain

#### **CELTA Course**

- · Work with elementary & upper intermediate students
- Taught more than 8 classes during the course

#### **DEC 2020 - JUNE 2022**

Instituto Cervantes Cartagena, Spain

Spanish Dele B2 Diploma Spanish Dele B1 Diploma

## **JUNE 2016**

Sacred Heart Computer College Nairobi, Kenya

#### Certificate in computer packages

#### **JAN 2013 - MAY 2016**

Thika School of Medical and Health Sciences Nairobi, Kenya **Diploma in Community Health and Development** 

Credit

# PERSONAL DEVELOPMENT -

## **JUNE 2018 - DEC 2019**

**AU-PAIR** 

- Mentoring a young person
- Ensuring confidentiality
- Ensuring the welfare of Children
- Training in child protection responsibilities

#### - LANGUAGES —

## **COMPUTER SKILLS**

Multilingual English Multilingual Swahili Multilingual Luo Advance Level Spanish Intermediate Level German Sufficient in using Microsoft Office, Google Docs, Skype, Zoom, Google Drive and One Drive

## - Hobbies -

# **MOBILITY**

## REFERENCES —

Travelling, culture, reading and socializing

Full clean Spain driving license

Anna Stubs, Course Director, Oxford TEFL, Barcelona coursedirector@oxfordtefl.com